<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on The DS Dev</title>
    <link>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on The DS Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:45:28 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Takes the Cake</title>
      <link>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/linux-takes-the-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:45:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/linux-takes-the-cake/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Linux! This article covers all things concerned with one of the world&amp;rsquo;s only free and open source operating systems.
The Linux kernel (the core of any operating system is called a kernel) was invented by Finnish software engineer Linus Torvalds in 1991, and subsequently named after him. Like many other operating systems, it is a derivative of UNIX..
Distributions The nice thing about open source software is that anybody can fork the project on GitHub (or another version control software), and create their own version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Homebrew</title>
      <link>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/getting-started-with-homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 16:08:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/getting-started-with-homebrew/</guid>
      <description>Homebrew is a popular package manager which has the ability to install almost any application or software in existence. To start using Homebrew, you&amp;amp;&amp;rsquo;ll have to open the command line, which is the &amp;ldquo;Terminal&amp;rdquo; app or program on Mac and Linux and &amp;ldquo;command.exe&amp;rdquo; on Windows.
Once in the application or program shown above, type the following command, and hit Return:
1  /bin/bash -c &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)   The /bin/bash should be changed to /bin/zsh on Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hive or Spark</title>
      <link>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/hive-or-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 16:08:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k-explorer.github.io/blog/posts/hive-or-spark/</guid>
      <description>Lots of data scientists wonder whether to use Apache Hive or Apache Spark. This article aims to condense the problem into a short comparison.
Dependencies Apache Hive runs on Apache Hadoop, a complex data warehouse built in Java. To use Hive, Hadoop must be installed and configured as well. Spark, on the other hand, originally required Hadoop but does not currently. Hive is it’s own Java library, but Spark has a different distribution for each of it’s three supported languages:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
